So, OpenAI just launched CHBD pulse and
it's actually insane. Well, it's a brand
new AI agent that works for you every
single day completely autonomously.
Basically, it turns CHBT from a passive
chatbot to an AI agent that's actually
proactive. In this video, I'll show you
what it does, how it works, and whether
it is worth the $200 a month. So, as of
today, Palace is only available on
mobile. So, make sure you install Chat
GBD on your phone. Now, when you open
the app, you can already see that in the
middle it says today's pulse. So,
they're really pushing this feature and
this is going to be one of the main
features inside of CH GBT. That is my
prediction. But you can also open it by
going to the left and clicking on pulse.
And this opens up your CHB pulse
overview for that day. Now, here is the
official announcement tweet from Sam
Ultman, the CEO of OpenAI. And by the
way, he does say that this is his
favorite feature of CHGBT. And I don't
think it's lying because this feature
it's really good. You'll see what I mean
in a bit. Anyways, Pulse works for you
overnight and keeps thinking about your
interests, your connected data, your
recent chats, and more. Every morning,
you get a custom generated set of stuff
you might be interested in. And let me
tell you, this is an understatement
because it really feels like pulse can
read your mind. It performs super well
if you tell CHBD more about what's
important to you. So, basically, when
chatting with it, tell it your current
goals. Tell it what problems you're
facing in your business or your life,
and it will use all of that context to
make pulse as good as possible. Here's
the next part of Sam Alman's tweet.
Think of treating Chad GBD like a super
competent personal assistant. Sometimes
you ask for things you need in the
moment, but if you share general
preferences, it will do a good job for
you proactively. And this is the main
thing, the first feature in the world
that's actually proactive, which means
it does stuff for you without you having
to ask. This also points to what I
believe is the future of CHIGBT, a shift
from being all reactive to being
significantly proactive and extremely
personalized. Let me show you an actual
example that kind of blew my mind. So
for context, few days ago, I asked JGBT
about which cities in Europe would be
the best to establish an in-person
office for vector, my startup. And it
was just a single chat. And look what
Pulse did with that information. So as
it says, you'll find this useful as
context when dealing with tech teams in
Poland. So Warso, the capital of Poland,
was one of the main cities I was
considering. and it used that context to
do detailed, deep research on what it's
like to hire in Poland and build a deaf
team. I didn't give it the instruction
to search for this. Now, I cannot stress
this enough. It might not seem
impressive to you because this is not
your problem. This is not something
you're thinking about, but this is hyper
relevant to me. So, when I read this, I
was like, "Wow, it literally predicted
what I was about to like search up or
research ahead of time." And by the way,
if you are a junior developer from
Europe and you might be interesting in
joining our Warsaw office, make sure to
apply. The link is going to be below the
video. Now, when I first saw this, the
first thought into my mind was how could
I build my own pulse? How could we build
a system like this? And actually
building something like change pulse is
much more doable than you think. The
biggest problem really is giving your AI
agent access to operate on the website
so that it can do the agentic proactive
behavior that you want it to do.
However, there's a solution that lets
you automate any actions in the browser
and give those powers to your AI agents.
And that solution is browserbased.
Browserbase lets you automate any
actions in the browser using natural
language. And it does so with stage
hand, which is their browser automation
framework. For example, you can run a
research agent to automate a task like
buy me a concert tickets for this artist
or you can use authenticated agent to
approve your teammates's pull requests
on GitHub. Now, creating these
automations is much easier than you
think because we can use director.ai to
do it for us. So, for example, I can
tell it, I want you to find me skilled
video editors on YouTube.co, navigate to
the talent section and filter categories
to video editors. So, this is an agentic
task and you can even watch it do the
automation for you. Like look at this.
It's opening the talent page, then it's
filtering by the categories, and you can
watch it work. Now, any automation you
create, just open it in playground, and
you can easily add it to your own
codebase. And on the left you can see
its thinking process. I notice I'm
currently on Google's homepage, not on
YouTube.co. Then it went to the website.
It clicked on the talent link and you
can see the reasoning it did after that.
Then it clicked on all categories and
it's creating the automation like that.
AI agent browsing the web in real time.
I mean the amount of potential startups
you can build with this is literally
endless. To try browser base yourself,
just use the link below the video. Thank
you to Browserbase for sponsoring this
video. All right, so let's look a bit
deeper on how Pulse actually works.
First off, it analyzes all of your
recent chats. So, if I had to guess,
probably like the re most recent 30 to
60 days of your chbd conversations. Then
it groups that into five to seven most
important topics that you actually care
about. This could be your goals,
problems, things you are currently
learning, some things you might just be
interested in. And then it does
extensive deep research on those topics,
searching how to solve those problems,
best practices, any recent news.
Basically, it does a bunch of work for
you. Now, to give it even more context,
you can also connect apps like email and
calendar, which if you think into
future, it's going to be able to do
those actions, not just, you know, get
your calendar to see what you have for
the week. It's going to be able to
schedule slots, respond to emails. Yeah,
this could get real crazy real soon, but
more on that later. And then every
morning inside of your mobile app, you
will receive your pulse, you know, your
summary for the day with five to eight
personalized mini articles that are
hyper relevant to you. I really cannot
emphasize that enough. Pulse only really
is useful if you use CHP every day and
if you give it enough context. Now, why
did OpenAI put this on the CH GBD Pro
plan which cost $200 a month? And the
reason is JBD pulse burns a lot of
tokens both on reasoning about your
goals, your recent chats, your interests
and on the deep research part and
processing all those tokens from the
research. And this is exactly why it
feels so relevant to you. Like it
literally feels like it can read your
mind because it does so much reasoning
and so much thinking, so many tokens it
processes and all of that costs actual
money, right? Openi has to run the GPUs
and that cost them money. So, I do not
think this is just a ploy to get more
people to upgrade to the most expensive
plan. I actually think that currently
they cannot make it any cheaper. But
they did say, however, that they are
soon going to release it for the $20 a
month plan. Maybe it won't be as
expensive. But hey, if you have JBD
Plus, something to be excited for. Okay,
so let me actually show you what this
looks like in the app. So today, 26th
September, we have it in here. And you
can see it's a series of mini articles
with AI generated images which are
nicely complementing the article.
They're hyper relevant to me. So the
first one is fast flexible task
ordering. Right? I'm building a task
management application vectal and this
is highly relevant. Next up persistent
memory for AI agents. This is probably
something I researched recently. And
then after like three articles it asks
you for feedback and this is really the
true power of it, right? Because in
order for this to be useful every single
day, it needs to keep getting context
from your brain. So it's asking you
decide what shows up here. What's on
your mind lately? I'll remember it for
tomorrow's update. And you can tell it
anything, right? So like I'm trying to
scale my startup faster and this is my
bottleneck. Or I'm trying to lose weight
and I need to help building a diet. Or
I'm trying to hire a person for this
position. Whatever your goal is,
whatever problem you're facing in life,
give it that context and you'll be
surprised how much work it does behind
the scenes. So if I scroll deeper, we
can see more articles. Here's a way to
make strategy progress clearer for
teammates. So I was thinking of how to
scale my team and how to organize tasks.
Then I was asking something about
mermaid diagrams. So let me actually
click on this article to get more
details. And you can see these are like
hyper relevant articles based on your
recent searches. Consider this database
upgrade only if you're ready to test and
benchmark. So it gives you these like
summaries or actionable tips. It's not
just like bloat where it, you know,
browses the web and gives you like
irrelevant article. All of this is hyper
relevant to my recent search queries and
there's another input field. So, they're
really trying hard to get your faults
and really fine-tune how good this is.
Which of these software development
practices do you want more updates on
database performance, code review tools,
system design diagrams? I'm going to go
with system design. So, I clicked on
that and now it's it's sent out as a
feedback and ch response. Got it. Thanks
for letting me know. I'll bring more
focus on system designs for upcoming
updates. And this is how they ensure
it's useful every single day because if
you're not using CHBD daily, if you're
not giving it enough info, it has
nothing to reason about. Let's talk
resilience. Why relying on just one AI
model might be risky. Another article.
Here's a simple offline doc. So this is
interesting. I was on a flight recently
from Europe to Dubai and I was setting
up offline dogs for Python because I
wanted to program on the plane and
clearly I asked JGB about it and now it
tells me a simple way to set up local
dogs with PI do. I mean I just
downloaded the whole Python
documentation in HTML but that's fine.
And when you scroll down to the bottom
you can see that's all for today.
Thinking ahead what do you want to see?
And again you can provide more feedback
to CHVD pulse to make it even more
relevant. Now, this is just the
beginning because soon proactive AI
agents like this will be everywhere and
they'll become mega useful for your
calendar, for your email, for your
entire life because there will be more
and more integrations, right? More MCP
style tools, more protocols, more
frameworks that will enable the AI
agents to do even more stuff than they
can do today. The main bottleneck really
will be the connectors, the software
that makes all of this possible, the
glue, if you will, that allows the AI
agents to operate. And the exciting part
is that it's up to us, people like you
and me, to build this and to invent this
technology so that AI agents can really
change the world. Hopefully, you found
this video useful. If you did, make sure
to subscribe. And with that being said,
I wish you a wonderful, productive week.
See you.